{
  "isTheory": true,
  "openingRemarks": "Find the solution to the following equations",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{2}{3}(3x + 9) = -2(2x + 6) \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{2}{3}(3x + 9) &= -2(2x + 6) \\\\\n3 \\times \\dfrac{2}{3}(3x + 9)  &= 3 \\times -2(2x + 6) \\\\\n2(3x + 9) &=  -6(2x + 6) \\\\\n6x + 18 &= -12x - 36 \\\\\n6x + 12x &= -36 -18 \\\\\n18x &= -54 \\\\\n\\dfrac{18x}{18} &= \\dfrac{-54}{18} \\\\\nx &= -3\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{2}{3}(3x + 9)\\) if \\(x=-3\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{2}{3}(3x + 9) &= \\dfrac{2}{3}(3(-3) + 9) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{2}{3}(-9 + 9) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{2}{3}(0) \\\\\n&= 0\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(-2(2x + 6)\\) if \\(x=-3\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-2(2x + 6) &= -2(2(-3) + 6) \\\\\n&= -2(-6 + 6)  \\\\\n&= -2(0) \\\\\n&= 0\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(2(2t + 4) = \\dfrac{3}{4}(24 - 8t)  \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2(2t + 4) &= \\dfrac{3}{4}(24 - 8t)  \\\\\n4 \\times 2(2t + 4) &= 4 \\times \\dfrac{3}{4}(24 - 8t)  \\\\\n8(2t + 4) &=  3(24 - 8t) \\\\\n16t + 32 &= 72 - 24t \\\\\n16t + 24t &= 72 - 32 \\\\\n40t &= 40 \\\\\n\\dfrac{40t}{40} &= \\dfrac{40}{40} \\\\\nt &= 1\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(2(2t + 4)\\) if \\(t=1\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2(2t + 4) &= 2(2(1) + 4) \\\\\n&= 2(2 + 4) \\\\\n&= 2(6) \\\\\n&= 12\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{3}{4}(24 - 8t)\\) if \\(t=1\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{3}{4}(24 - 8t) &= \\dfrac{3}{4}(24 - 8(1)) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{3}{4}(24 - 8)  \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{3}{4}(16) \\\\\n&= 12\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(10(2y + 2) - y = 2(8y - 8)  \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n10(2y + 2) - y &= 2(8y - 8)  \\\\\n20y + 20 - y &= 16y - 16 \\\\\n20y - y - 16y &= -16 - 20 \\\\\n3y &= -36 \\\\\n\\dfrac{3y}{3} &= \\dfrac{-36}{3} \\\\\ny &= -12\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(10(2y + 2) - y\\) if \\(y=-12\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n10(2y + 2) - y &= 10(2(-12) + 2) - (-12) \\\\\n&= 10(-24 + 2) + 12 \\\\\n&= 10(-22) + 12 \\\\\n&= -220 + 12\n&= -208\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(2(8y - 8)\\) if \\(y=-12\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2(8y - 8) &= 2(8(-12) - 8) \\\\\n&= 2(-96 - 8)  \\\\\n&= 2(-104) \\\\\n&= -208\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(2(4x + 2) = 4x - 12(x - 1)  \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2(4x + 2) &= 4x - 12(x - 1)  \\\\\n8x + 4 &= 4x - 12x + 12 \\\\\n8x - 4x + 12x &= 12 - 4 \\\\\n16x &= 8 \\\\\n\\dfrac{16x}{16} &= \\dfrac{8}{16} \\\\\nx &= \\frac{1}{2}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(2(4x + 2)\\) if \\(x=\\frac{1}{2}\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2(4x + 2) &= 2\\left(4\\left(\\dfrac{1}{2}\\right) + 2\\right) \\\\\n&= 2(2 + 2) \\\\\n&= 2(4) \\\\\n&= 8\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(4x - 12(x - 1)\\) if \\(x=\\frac{1}{2}\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4x - 12(x - 1) &= 4\\left(\\dfrac{1}{2}\\right) - 12\\left(\\dfrac{1}{2} - 1\\right) \\\\\n&= 2 - 12\\left(-\\dfrac{1}{2}\\right)  \\\\\n&= 2 - -6 \\\\\n&= 2 + 6 \\\\\n&= 8\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(x+ 9 = 7 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nx+ 9 &= 7 \\\\\nx &= 7 - 9 \\\\\nx &= -2\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 7</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(x + 9\\) if \\(x=-2\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nx + 9 &= -2 + 9 \\\\\n&= 7 \\\\\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(8.6 = z - 3.8 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n8.6 &= z - 3.8 \\\\\n8.6 + 3.8 &= z \\\\\n12.4 &= z \\\\\nz &= 12.4\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check 8.6 = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(z - 3.8\\) if \\(z=12.4\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nz - 3.8 &= 12.4 - 3.8 \\\\\n&= 8.6 \\\\\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(60 = -12r \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n60 &= -12r \\\\\n\\dfrac{60}{-12} &= \\dfrac{-12r}{-12} \\\\\n-5 &= r \\\\\nr &= -5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check 60 = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(-12r\\) if \\(r=-5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-12r &= -12(-5) \\\\\n&= 60 \\\\\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{3}{4}p = 18 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{3}{4}p &= 18 \\\\\n4 \\times \\dfrac{3}{4}p &= 4 \\times 18 \\\\\n3p &= 72 \\\\\n\\dfrac{3p}{3} &= \\dfrac{72}{3} \\\\\np &= 24\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 18</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{3}{4}p\\) if \\(p=24\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{3}{4}p &= \\dfrac{3}{4}(24) \\\\\n&= 18 \\\\\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(2m - 3 = 13 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2m - 3 &= 13 \\\\\n2m &= 13 + 3 \\\\\n2m &= 16 \\\\\n\\dfrac{2m}{2} &= \\dfrac{16}{2} \\\\\nm &= 8\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 13</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(2m - 3\\) if \\(m=8\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2m - 3 &= 2(8) - 3 \\\\\n&= 16 - 3 \\\\\n&= 13\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(5 = 10 - v \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n5 &= 10 - v \\\\\nv &= 10 - 5 \\\\\nv &= 5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check 5 = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(10 - v\\) if \\(v=5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n10 - v &= 10 - 5 \\\\\n&= 5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    }
  ]
}
